[
  {
   "id": 1,
   "question":"Visual acuity is affected by all of these factors except",
   "options": [
     "size of the pupil",
     "luminance",
     "contrast",
     "error of refraction",
     "source of visual stimuli"
    ],
   "answer": ["source of visual stimuli"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 2,
   "question":"Humans can detect sound in the frequency range of",
   "options": [
     "100 Hz - 20,000 Hz",
     "50 Hz - 10,000 Hz",
     "20 Hz - 20,000 Hz",
     "50Hz - 20,000 Hz",
     "40 Hz - 10,000 Hz"
    ],
   "answer": ["20 Hz - 20,000 Hz"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 3,
   "question":"Which of these is not related to the optic nerve ?",
   "options": [
     "it is made up of ganglion cell axons",
     "it exit the eye through the optic disc",
     "each optic nerve has about 1.2 million nerve fibres",
     "it consists of nasal and temporal retina fibres",
     "each of the nerve result in bitemporal hemianopia"
    ],
   "answer": ["each of the nerve result in bitemporal hemianopia"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 4,
   "question":"Photopic vision is primarily associated with",
   "options": [
     "rod cells",
     "cone cells",
     "ganglion cells",
     "bipolar cells",
     "ciliary bodies"
    ],
   "answer": ["cone cells"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 5,
   "question":"In the mechanism of hearing, which of these activities is incorrect?",
   "options": [
     "external ear collects and funnels sound to tympanic membrane",
     "ossicles vibrate, amplify sound and vibrate against the round window",
     "the scala vestibule and scala tympani contain perilymph",
     "the scala media contains the endolymph which vibrates the basilar membrane",
     "the hair cells of the organ corti generate endocochlea potential"
    ],
   "answer": ["ossicles vibrate, amplify sound and vibrate against the round window"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 6,
   "question":"Which of these statements best describe the iris?",
   "options": [
     "pigmented structure in front of the lens",
     "controls the amount of light entering the eye",
     "consist of circular and radial smooth muscles",
     "it comes in several fashionable colours"
    ],
   "answer": ["pigmented structure in front of the lens"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 7,
   "question":"The shape of the lens is controlled by",
   "options": [
     "oculomotor nerve",
     "ciliary muscle",
     "object distance from the eye",
     "size of the pupil",
     "suspensory ligaments"
    ],
   "answer": ["ciliary muscle"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 8,
   "question":"In optics of the eye, light enters the eye through",
   "options": ["ciliary muscle","sclera","pupil","iris","lens"],
   "answer": ["pupil"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 9,
   "question":"Visual pathway begin at the",
   "options": [
     "lens",
     "retina",
     "optic chiasm",
     "lateral geniculate matter",
     "optic radiation"
    ],
   "answer": ["retina"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 10,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within scala vestibule",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Perilymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 11,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within Cochlear duct",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Endolymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 12,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within semicircular duct",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Endolymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 13,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within Utricle",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Endolymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 14,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within scala typmpani",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Perilymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 15,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within vestibule",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Endolymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 16,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within semicircular canal",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Perilymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 17,
   "question":"what type of fluid is found within saccule",
   "options": [
     "Perilymph",
     "Endolymph",
     "Intracellular fluid",
     "Extracellular fluid"
    ],
   "answer": ["Endolymph"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 18,
   "question":"Light rays entering the eye are focused mainly by _________ and __________ on the retina",
   "options": [
     "Cornea and lens",
     "aqueous humour and vitreous humour",
     "conjunctiva and lens",
     "sclera and lens",
     "ciliary muscles and lens"
    ],
   "answer": ["Cornea and lens"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 19,
   "question":" Which of the following is not associated with the layers of the eye?",
   "options": [
     "protective and maintenance of the shape of eyeball",
     "provides attachment sites for extrinsic muscles of the eyes",
     "pigmentation and nourishment of the eye",
     "interpretation of impulses into visual images",
     "transduction of light energy into nerve impulses"
    ],
   "answer": ["interpretation of impulses into visual images"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 20,
   "question":"The special senses perform all these duties except ?",
   "options": [
     "being essential for life",
     "survival in our environment",
     "give us the capacity to see, hear, smell and taste the wonder of the world around us",
     "anticipation for food, write and decision making",
     "seek and participation in social symphony of life"
    ],
   "answer": ["being essential for life"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 21,
   "question":"Sweet taste is located in which part of the tongue?",
   "options": [
     "back of the tongue",
     "tip of the tongue",
     "posterior side of the tongue",
     "anterior side of the tongue",
     "center of the tongue"
    ],
   "answer": ["tip of the tongue"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 22,
   "question":"The difference in composition of endolymph from other lymph in the body is;",
   "options": [
     "in high concentration of K+ ion",
     "high concentration of Na +",
     "low (Cl-) ion",
     "low concentration of Ca2+",
     "low concentration of Na+ ion"
    ],
   "answer": ["in high concentration of K+ ion"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 23,
   "question":"Which of these bones vibrates against oval window of the inner ear?",
   "options": [
     "malleus",
     "tympanic membrane",
     "tympanic antrum",
     "stapes",
     "incus"
    ],
   "answer": ["stapes"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 24,
   "question":"Image is laterally inverted in the retina due to",
   "options": [
     "lens refraction of light",
     "focal length of the object",
     "focal length of the image",
     "focal point of the object",
     "focal point of the imag"
    ],
   "answer": ["lens refraction of light"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 25,
   "question":"The two major types of photoreceptor cells are:",
   "options": [
     "bipolar and ganglion cells",
     "amacrine and bipolar cells",
     "cone and rod cells",
     "erythrolabe and cones",
     "cyanolabe and rods"
    ],
   "answer": ["cone and rod cells"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 26,
   "question":"The inner segment of the photoreceptor cells harbours the machinery for _________ and ________",
   "options": [
     "light absorption and impulse generation",
     "protein synthesis and energy production",
     "transduction and visual interpretation",
     "Impulse generation and contrast",
     "visual memories and information"
    ],
   "answer": ["transduction and visual interpretation"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 27,
   "question":"Which of these constitute the 3rd order neurons in the visual pathway",
   "options": [
     "ganglion cells",
     "bipolar cells",
     "optic radiation",
     "optic nerve",
     "optic chiasma"
    ],
   "answer": ["optic radiation"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 28,
   "question":"The optic tract consists of",
   "options": [
     "nasal fibres and temporal fibres of the retina",
     "decussated nasal fibres and ipsilateral temporal fibres",
     "decussated temporal fibres and nasal fibres of the same side",
     "Optic radiation and optic nerve",
     "lateral geniculatr fibres and optic radiation"
    ],
   "answer": ["decussated nasal fibres and ipsilateral temporal fibres"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 29,
   "question":"The motions of the body is detected by",
   "options": [
     "organ of corti",
     "ossicles",
     "semi circular canals",
     "membranous endolymph",
     "utricle and saccule"
    ],
   "answer": ["semi circular canals"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 30,
   "question":"Obstruction of the scleral venous sinus (canal of schlemm ) interferes with the",
   "options": [
     "drainage of vitreous humour",
     "drainage of the tarsal glands",
     "drainage of aqueous humour",
     "drainage of tears into the lacrimal sac",
     "flow of blood through the ciliary blood capillaries"
    ],
   "answer": ["drainage of aqueous humour"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":""
  },
  {
   "id": 31,
   "question":"Which of the special senses receptor cells are replenished throughout life",
   "options": [
     "olfactory",
     "gustatory",
     "organ of corti",
     "the rods",
     "the cones"
    ],
   "answer": ["olfactory"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 32,
   "question":"All of these functions are traceable to the cone except ?",
   "options": [
     "cone are used to determine colour vision, depth and intensity",
     "cone provide photopic , high acuity and daytime vision",
     "cones require rhodopsin, low light energy and three different cell type",
     "cones are centrally located in the retina layer",
     "cone are fewer in number than rods and less sensitive to motion than rods"
    ],
   "answer": ["cones require rhodopsin, low light energy and three different cell type"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 33,
   "question":"All but one of these processes begins at the retina",
   "options": [
     "Contrast",
     "brightness",
     "motion",
     "stereopsis",
     "all of the above"
    ],
   "answer": ["motion"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 34,
   "question":"Which of the statements incorrect of myopia",
   "options": [
     "lens refracture is too strong",
     "eyeball is too long",
     "corrected by a convex lens",
     "genetically inherited"
    ],
   "answer": ["corrected by a convex lens"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 35,
   "question":"Light enters the eye through the",
   "options": ["conjunctiva","sclera","pupil","lens"],
   "answer": ["pupil"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 36,
   "question":"In the visual field the temporal hemifield of each eyes project to",
   "options": [
     "optic chiasm",
     "nasal retinal fibres",
     "lateral geniculate nuclei",
     "temporal retinal retinal fibres",
     "fovea centralis"
    ],
   "answer": ["nasal retinal fibres"],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  },
  {
   "id": 37,
   "question":"Which of these is not associated with the eye layer",
   "options": [
     "protective and maturation",
     "provides attachment sites of extrinsic muscle of the eye",
     "pigmentation and nourishment of the eye",
     "on of impulses to the visual image",
     "interpretation of transduction of light energy into nerve impulses."
    ],
   "answer": ["interpretation of transduction of light energy into nerve impulses."],
   "explanation":"",
   "topic":"Special senses"
  }
]
